JOSEPH BRIMEYER

206-396-3998

JBrimeyer@Gmail.com

I am a highly effective business leader with over 15 years of managerial experience in manufacturing and distribution operations. I am actively pursuing new opportunities in full stack web development. I am skilled in C#, JavaScript, j Query, ajax, API's, HTML, CSS, GitHub, and SAP ERP software. Please contact me to learn more about how I can contribute to your organization.

EXPERIENCE

OCT 2018 - MAY 2019

DISTRIBUTION MARKET LEADER, DAWN FOOD PRODUCTS, INC.

Performed the role of General Manager for two distribution centers. Responsible for the overall financial performance of the DC's with \$50 million in annual sales. Supported the SAP ERP system for the organization. Specialist in SAP WM, SCM, QM, and IM. Directed administrative activities related to distribution operations. Reviewed financial statements, sales reports, and other performance data to measure productivity and goal achievement. Identified areas needing cost reduction and program improvement. Utilize BI reporting to make intelligent business decisions. Coordinate activities of 50 full-time personnel involved with sales and distribution services. Prepare staff work schedules and assigned specific duties by position. Evaluated supplier performance to ensure that they efficiently and effectively provided needed goods and services within budgetary limits. Enforced safety and food safety compliance. I provided an exceptional level of customer service as a preferred supplier to the bakery industry in the Pacific Northwest.

FEB 2006 - OCT 2018

OPERATIONS MANAGER, DAWN FOOD PRODUCTS, INC.

Supported sales growth of over \$40 million during my tenure. Conducted training and operational support for 10 SAP implementations at Dawn facilities throughout the country. My distribution center was the SAP pilot location for the organization. I was promoted to Distribution Market Leader in 2018. Conducted weekly staff meetings and monthly corporate training for my teams. Managed all activities related to strategic purchasing, material requirement planning, inventory control, equipment maintenance, stock rotation, warehousing, shipping, and receiving. Determined appropriate equipment and staffing levels to load, unload, move, and store materials. Managed the transportation department to control expenses by territories. Defined performance metrics for measurement, comparison, and evaluation of supply chain factors, such as product cost and quality. Implemented new and improved supply chain processes to improve efficiencies and performance.

DISTRIBUTION MANAGER, BUNGE LTD.

Managed the activities of workers engaged in receiving, storing, and shipping raw materials and finished goods. Planned, developed, and implemented warehouse safety and security programs and activities. Inspected physical conditions of the warehouse, vehicle fleets, and equipment. Scheduled maintenance, repairs, and replacements. Enforced safe workplace practices, SOP's, and GMP's for a manufacturing facility. Responded to customers' and shippers' questions regarding storage and distribution services. Developed and documented standard and emergency operating procedures for receiving, handling, storing, and shipping materials. Reduced headcount by 18% while increasing distribution output and operating income by streamlining roles and responsibilities of my team utilizing CI principles.

EDUCATION

SEPTEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON PROFESSIONAL & CONTINUING EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Coding Boot Camp. Foundations of Programming (C# and .NET).

MASTER'S DEGREE DEPAUL UNIVERSITY

BACHELOR'S DEGREE CORNELL COLLEGE

SKILLS

- SAP implementations and execution.
- JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3.
- ¡Query, ajax and API's.
- GitHub
- C# and .NET framework.
- Node.js
- Utilize technology to drive business growth.

- Leadership and Management.
- Crisis Management.
- Continuous Improvement.
- HACCP, HazMat, and Food Safety.
- Strong critical thinking skills.
- Budgetary Planning.
- WISHA, L&I, OSHA, EPA, and DOT Compliance.

VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

- -Volunteer with Boy Scouts of America from 2014 to present. Served as the Assistant Scout Master, Committee Chair, Secretary, and Communications Officer. Assisted with youth advancement, fundraising, planned and supervised group outings.
- -Volunteer with CYO Athletics as head basketball coach from 2017 to present. Lead youth to improved skills, character development, and sportsmanship.